WHEN LIFE GIVES YOU TANGERINES
DAUGHTER OF YANG GWAN-SIK AND OH AE-SUN
YANG GEUM-MYEONG! ACCEPTED TO SNU!
'88 SEOUL OLYMPICS CELEBRATION
ADVANCED CITIZENS! ADVANCED STREETS!
Who cares
if you're from the Olympics?
Haenyeo do more than Olympians every day!
For the haenyeo,
their "Olympics"
was simply making ends meet.
Please, everyone, calm down.
If you'd just let us explain.
And the Olympic events
they competed in
were as grand as they were cruel.
Games without medals,
pensions,
or retirement.
What the hell are you ruining
our business for?
Why? Go do your Olympics
if that's what you want.
- Why do we have to sacrifice for it?
- Oh God.
Who are you trying to punish here?
Who ever saw a conch
protesting the Olympics?
Or a fish blocking the roads?
All right! Enough!
Seriously! I've had enough.
We need to get through!
How many times do I have to tell you?
The Olympic torch
will be passing right through here!
Americans are going to watch this
on their TVs!
We can't let anyone see that.
All these disgusting intestines
and the smell of fish guts here?
Are you stupid or what?
Can you smell your TV?
We have orders from the government
to clean up anything unsightly.
That's an order!
- Why you little…
- Unsightly, eh?
Now I've heard it all.
You're going to take away our livelihoods
just to serve some Americans
thousands of miles away?
Does that make
any kind of sense to you at all?
Is that the American way
of doing business?
Trampling the poor
by taking the food out of our mouths!
I can't take this.
Oh, come on,
you're no crusaders for justice.
You're just fish-sellers like I am.
I think we can all handle
a little loss for the greater good.
Now stop messing things up!
I know what happened.
They paid you off, didn't they?
What? 'Cause I don't have
enough money yet, you think?
How much was it, huh?
How much did they pay you
for our blood, sweat, and tears?
You call yourself "chief"?
Maybe you would have some manners
if you had gone to school.
Explain it to us again!
The Olympic torch will pass through
for a few minutes,
and just for that,
you wanna take away our income?
What kind of law is that?
- Oh, please. What about it?
- Go away!
What do you know about the law?
Oh Ae-sun!
Where's Ae-sun?
Go get our deputy chief.
She finished high school.
Finished high school?
- She didn't even graduate.
- Well, she went at least.
Where is our deputy chief?
- She would know exactly what to say!
- Ae-sun!
What are you shouting about
Ae-sun for?
It's not like she can do anything.
I want you to explain
how not selling our fish helps the nation.
God, can't you see this doesn't matter?
If North Korea decides
to ruin our Olympics
and bursts the Mount Kumgang dam,
all of Seoul will be flooded.
Even the 63 Building
would be under the sea.
Don't you follow the news?
Don't you understand?
It's for the greater good.
Compared to history,
your little lives don't matter at all.
Yes, they do. Yes, they do.
- You bet your ass they matter.
- Oh, it's hopeless.
Do you know how riots get started?
If you kick over a dog's bowl of food,
it's gonna start shitting
all over the place!
- Is that what you want?
- Let go.
Is that what you want?
Huh?
- Ae-sun!
- No, no, no.
- That's not what I want.
- Ae-sun!
Hey! She's right there.
Right there. Here she is.
- Ae-sun, there you are.
- She'll tell you.
Well?
Wait. Deputy.
Deputy.
She's not gonna start shitting here,
is she?
Hey, get up.
There's an outcry with no sound
What's that?
Lashed by the season's bitter scourge
You're embarrassing yourself.
Stop making a scene.
- If you get fed up with me and--
- Hey, someone get a forklift.
Then run me over!
Hey, this is a gangster.
She's not a high school graduate.
The only gangsters here are the ones
stealing people's livelihoods.
What? You can't be serious!
Bring it on!
Oh, now I'm really getting pissed off!
Just tell them to pack it up! Come on!
I said, bring it on!
Do your worst!
My goodness,
what happened to the bookworm?
Well, I know what. I know what.
Life happened, that's what.
I don't believe it.
Damn it.
Hey, Bu Sang-gil.
A FRUITFUL FALL
You better compensate us
for the day of lost sales!
OPPOSITION PARTIES FAIL TO AGREE
ON SINGLE CANDIDACY
Politics is as fickle as the wind,
isn't it?
The whole town is talking about
how you could be the next village chief.
Please. I told you.
I have no interest in politics.
That's what you types always say.
Then, lo and behold, you end up running.
This election is between
a government stooge
and real fighters like us.
If we let
that treacherous idiot of a chief
win with all the money
from the Olympic bureaucrats,
then all of us haenyeo are screwed.
If he wants to get called "chief,"
he should be acting like one, right?
I hate how he calls you "deputy"
all the time.
It's all, "Hey, deputy" this,
"deputy" that!
"Hey, deputy!"
- That's how he says it.
- She can't stand being a number two.
If a dog like him can be the chief,
then why not her?
Let's make a haenyeo's daughter
village chief.
Will you cut it out?
I have no interest in politics.
I told you that.
Oh?
So we should just ignore
what your husband wants?
Wow, this is a first.
It looks like our captain
is on the campaign trail.
All right, you gave us snacks.
Who should we vote for?
We took the bribe, Captain.
Talk to us.
Well,
I don't say this because she's my wife.
She has been a natural leader.
She's been guiding us often.
I witnessed it myself.
More than that, she's smart. In fact,
I've never in my life met anyone smarter.
That's my honest opinion.
Sure, she was smart enough
to make you captain.
Hey.
Let's be frank here.
Are you really okay with
Ae-sun being the village chief?
Your wife would be the first female
village chief Dodong-ri has ever had.
What happens to you?
I'm not sure if that's
respectable for a man.
Sure, she'd be the first, but so would I.
If Ae-sun becomes
the first female chief of the village,
then that would make me
the first husband of the chief.
That's respectable.
I wouldn't even
have to do anything at all.
Well, just slow down, huh?
You're making the rest of us men look bad.
Our captain's dreams
sure sound different from ours.
Here, they just came out with this brand.
All of it. I'm going to be
the chief of the fishing village,
and then I'll be president
five times in a row.
When you grow up, what will you be?
What are you asking him for?
- Goodness.
- Oh my.
The First Gentleman.
Well…
What is it, First Lady?
Those drinks,
there are actually
real, fresh bananas in there.
This is the best quality, you guys.
I see you like it.
It's all right,
but this banana milk is nothing.
That bigwig you're running against
is giving away pork.
Who doesn't love pork?
Listen up.
This isn't just any old pork.
This is Jeju black pork.
Oh yes.
From Jeju Island black pig.
Make sure everyone gets a double serving
of this premium meat.
Premium? This is what we always serve.
Listen up, everybody.
Don't think I have an ulterior motive.
Really, I'm not doing this
for money or honor.
My only concern is, and always has been,
"How can I give the folks
in our village something good?"
"How can I give folks something to enjoy?"
Can I have some water?
- Garlic, please.
- Water, please.
Could you at least listen to me
when I'm talking to you? Sheesh.
I don't know why
you squeezed us all in here
just to feed us a morsel of pork.
Finish your plate, Grandma.
Then you can order more.
You don't look like one of my supporters,
but here you are.
She's right. You're barely feeding them.
You're frugal, I'll give you that.
So, think about it.
Oh Ae-sun has basically
no history to speak of
whereas my family built this town
and continues to serve!
I ordered soda an hour ago.
When are you gonna serve that?
Not everyone is born a leader,
which is exactly why
we should carefully examine
each candidate's past to check
for any issues or family problems.
What family problems?
I heard Gwan-sik
got an official commendation.
- Do you have any of those?
- It's not a commendation, all right?
It's a plaque of appreciation.
I could get a dozen of those things,
no problem.
But you don't have any.
Have you ever saved anyone from drowning?
Stop talking over me! Hush.
You should learn to listen
when someone is talking to you.
All you ladies just want to butt in
the first chance you get, aren't you?
What about you? Why don't you
listen to me about that soda?
Now, as I was saying,
that family isn't exactly
a shining example of behavior.
At 18, they stole high-end jewelry
and ran off together.
- Their daughter was conceived like that.
- She's at Seoul National University.
Well, the second child is a rotten egg!
I don't wanna speak ill
of other people's kids, but him?
- It's hard to say anything good.
- Okay, then don't.
Bring my soda instead.
I'm saying the apple
never falls far from the tree.
When you start with parents like those,
what do you expect to come out?
It's in their genes!
DODONG-RI FISHING CO-OP DEPUTY CHIEF
MOTHER OF YANG EUN-MYEONG
DODONG-RI FISHING CO-OP CHIEF
Did you come here
from the hair salon?
Take that off.
So how many other student officers are
bringing their mothers to school today?
I can't believe they made you PE leader.
Of all people.
It's just too funny.
Oh goodness.
I'm sure the other mothers
will have so many questions for me.
Like how your sister made it
into Seoul University.
I'll be they'll wanna know
what our secret was.
About that.
It's at 4:00, right? Let's go.
- Mom.
- Ooh, I hope I'm not too early.
- Mom, wait.
- Is this where all the mothers are?
There are no other mothers.
Why? I thought
this was for all the student officers.
- It's actually just for us.
- What?
Hello, sir. I can't tell you how--
No need to come in, ma'am.
- Follow me outside.
- Huh?
To the parking lot?
Apparently, I drive an Onata now!
And another teacher just discovered
he's driving a Hyundai Pon!
The students believe if they get
the initials to their dream colleges,
it will help with their odds
of getting in.
Is that the way your sister did it?
And… and he's not just
stealing these letters.
He's actually selling them off!
Ma'am, I shouldn't have to tell you
how serious this is.
Just look at the principal's car!
Have you ever heard of a Tellar GX?
I've been teaching for more than 20 years.
And in that time,
no student has turned my car
into an Onata until Yang Eun-myeong!
I'm sorry, sir.
He only comes to school
for his side hustles.
He's certainly good with his hands.
He's always scheming. Whether it's cutting
a set of ten bus tickets into eleven
for a profit of 50 won
or playing the coin flipping game
and stealing the coin
when no one's looking.
School isn't a business!
It's not a job.
Only the teachers should be getting paid.
He probably makes more money
at this school than I do.
I'm sorry, sir.
You cared so much for your daughter
that you've completely neglected your son.
Do you even know what kind of students
he's hanging out with?
That's right, stay away from me.
I don't wanna hear a word.
"All the mothers will be there."
Well, you got me.
What's with these little schemes anyway?
Why can't you just study
like you're supposed to?
Why are you so obsessed with money?
You know, I was never embarrassed
at school when your sister was here.
But now I can't look
your teacher in the eye!
Stop hitting the trees!
What's going on with you?
Where did we go wrong?
I said we'd be happy
if you're even half like your sister.
Was that too much to ask?
Right, if I'm not like her,
you can't be chief.
My bad genes are holding you back.
No, that's--
Where did you hear that?
- Bu Sang-gil, that jerk.
- You don't have to lie.
You've always loved her more than me.
The son might be trouble,
but her daughter is a scholar.
Education isn't everything,
is it?
Can education change who her mother is?
Sure, she's at that fancy school…
…but she'll throw it all away
for some boy first chance she gets.
CELEBRATING DIRECT PRESIDENTIAL
ELECTION SYSTEM
♪ That my life would change forever… ♪
He's always coming to pick her up.
Is that her boyfriend?
I guess he's well-off.
Even if he is, how can a college student
drive that kind of car?
You know, something's up with her.
I saw it on TV.
Lots of college girls are escorts.
They get paid to go on dates
with older guys and pretend to like them.
Ju-gyeong, listen,
you gotta watch your mouth.
♪ Real fantasy ♪
♪ Illusions are a common thing ♪
♪ I try to live in dreams ♪
♪ It seems as… ♪
He's gotta be from
the US, right?
Look at him. How embarrassing.
He's opening the door and everything.
Does he also slice
pork cutlets for her at restaurants?
♪ A different kind of reality ♪
♪ I dream of loving in the night ♪
♪ And loving seems all right… ♪
Get in.
♪ Fantasy ♪
♪ All you need is love ♪
♪ Ba-ba-da-ba-da ♪
Hmm.
You just have to remember
who that girl's parents are,
and the future becomes clear.
I can see it already.
That whole family just has
no… no concept of decency at all.
Don't you think?
Boop!
Fine, so you bought the tree,
but you can't take credit for the rock.
You just wrote your name
on public property.
When you get down to it,
Ae-sun doesn't even deserve to be deputy.
Who does she think she is?
She knows nothing at all.
Hey, Captain. Are you actually
running on anything or what?
What?
Because it seems like you're running
just to trash-talk your opponent.
It's not talking trash.
It's just discussing morality.
The people have a right to know
who their candidates are, don't they?
BADA SEAFOOD HOUSE
I can't believe that scumbag
brought your kids into this.
- It's outrageous.
- Sang-gil crossed the line.
You need to fight back.
If you keep talking like that,
Ae-sun will have to respond.
She's been holding back
because she's got some class.
- But if push comes to shove…
- Oh yes. That's right.
…I imagine she'd have
a thing or two to say about you.
I remember his father
back during the occupation.
He couldn't wait to take on
a Japanese name!
Funny.
But you're not gonna find
any dirt on our side.
After all,
I make contributions to our government,
But Oh Ae-sun, well,
I'm pretty sure she's never
given as much as a dime to charity.
Politics is a land
of dog shit anyway.
If you have to roll in it,
better to have black fur than white.
If you roll in crap,
you get dirty all the same.
Black fur or not.
I'll win, but I won't change.
Oh, that's our Oh Ae-sun,
just as proud as ever.
You're not giving out soap.
You're not feeding them pork.
You're not even playing dirty.
Well, you might just lose. You might lose.
Ae-sun, it's only fair.
The villagers have a right to know
exactly who Sang-gil is.
And he already crossed the line
to attack you.
You may as well get him back too!
Hey, a caterpillar will get eaten
if it stays in its cocoon too long.
If that caterpillar struggles
and breaks out of its shell,
it flies away a butterfly.
You need to jump over the hurdle
before you fight your way out, Ae-sun.
♪ Clock strikes upon the hour
And the sun begins to fade ♪
♪ Still enough time to figure out ♪
♪ How to chase Ae-sun away ♪
♪ She's done all right up till now ♪
♪ But I'll win reelection anyhow ♪
♪ And when the night falls upon us ♪
♪ Bu Sang-gil calls ♪
♪ Da, da, da, da! ♪
♪ Oh, if you wanna vote for me ♪
♪ You can't find any dirt ♪
Stop it, jeez!
I'm not voting for someone
who ruins my appetite!
Are those noodles coming?
Mr. Gu, I think you'd sing better.
He's always on his wife's case, isn't he?
What's taking you so long
to cook those noodles?
You're walking home tonight.
You're not allowed in my car, understand?
Hey, Bu Sang-gil,
isn't it a bit ironic
your last name means "deputy?"
Maybe you should just accept
that no matter where you go,
you'll always be second fiddle.
- What?
- Are you even voting for me?
Or did you just come here
to make trouble or what?
Is this 'cause I didn't get you a soda?
Hey, if you do end up losing,
here's some advice.
Why would I lose?
Do you have any idea how much I've spent
on pork and noodles already, hmm?
Don't settle for anything less
than deputy chief.
It's like when you're watching Jeopardy,
and someone gets out ahead
only to finish last.
There's nothing more pathetic, is there?
Spare yourself and finish second at least.
- Hey!
- "Hey"?
Did you just "hey" me?
Where the hell are those noodles?
You can vote for Oh Ae-sun if you want.
FROM BU SANG-GIL, CANDIDATE 1
But no matter how smart the Oh family is
or how undeserving the Bu family may be,
there's no woman chief anywhere in Korea.
- No, of course not.
- Wow. A box of cigarettes each?
There's more?
I wish every day was election day.
Who can stand in the way of a typhoon?
Democracy is just data.
That's how it goes.
I vote Bu Sang-gil!
- I'll drink to that! Drink!
- Raise a glass.
Here, pour me some.
Yeah, that's it.
- Who's your chief?
- Mr. Bu!
- Who is your chief?
Lucky you.
I hope you're the chief till you die.
What can I say?
Indecency seems to run in the Oh family.
Just have a look at my own daughters.
Hyeon-suk, which stands for
"wise" and "enlightened,"
and Jeong-suk,
which stands for "silent."
Oh, he's a damn fool
if there ever was one.
I have…
I have absolutely nothing
in my past to be ashamed of, Mi-suk.
Life's a bitch, huh?
It's always so difficult
to get anything done.
You can sell everything
in the display case
and still wind up with nothing.
There's hardly any money to be made from
a real estate office on a tiny island.
I thought that helping out
the Olympics Committee was my big break,
but those haenyeo are so stubborn.
You know what I'm like.
- Mm.
- I'm a softie.
Mi-suk, I swear… I'll take care of it.
I'm your guy.
I'm practically a shoo-in
for reelection now.
Really?
You'd take care of everything
just like that?
I wouldn't even have to pay
a fee or anything, Bu Sang-gil?
30%.
What?
30/70 split.
Oh, all right.
After all,
cooperation makes the world go round.
Mi-suk, I'm your guy.
Dodong-ri's own Bu Sang-gil.
Mi-suk.
Listen.
I may have money, but I don't have
enough romance in my life.
I'm really quite a lonely guy.
You don't have to be shy.
Oh, I'm not.
Come on.
You don't think I'm offering
to help you for the money, do you?
Well, if it's not for the money,
then what's it for?
Don't make that face.
What face?
It's the Olympics, after all.
Walls are falling down all over the world,
even in the Soviet Union.
We could just break down the wall
in between us two.
Stop drinking.
You'll ruin your liver.
Oh.
But the quickest way to a man's heart
is through his stomach.
Perhaps this isn't just a piece of fish
but a trap for my stomach,
and my heart has taken the bait.
Maybe.
Oh, thank you.
These abalones are helping my heart
come out of its shell.
Shut up and eat your shrimp.
Your shrimp is really sending
the blood rushing to my… "muscle."
You're so dirty!
Wait, wait, I'm talking about…
It's my heart.
I mean my heart.
The blood's rushing to my heart.
Oh my God, you're such a clown.
Oh! You're awful!
Hey, listen.
I thought this was just dinner.
Why are you tormenting my lonely heart?
Huh?
- You're a naughty girl, aren't you?
- That tickles.
Disgusting.
Is this how you think
a village chief should act?
You need to jump over the hurdle
before you fight your way out, Ae-sun.
Oh my.
Wait, where are you going?
Damn it, what the hell
did you come in here for?
Well, well, well, if it isn't
"Mr. Snitch-for-the-government."
God, meongge guts are less gross than you.
Who the hell are you
to judge me?
What I do in private
is none of your goddamn business!
Well, we work here. Remember? Moron.
While you were telling that woman
the quickest way to a man's heart,
she was cracking
your wallet open like meongge.
Why were you
eavesdropping on us?
- Why?
- I just realized.
You're only village chief
so you can massage
the feet of another man's wife!
How dare you speak to me like that!
Whatever your reasons,
you sure can't be chief anymore.
Why can't I be chief though? Tell me.
You're like a stray dog who goes around
sticking his nose
into everyone's business.
Are you really surprised eventually
people would get fed up with you?
Yeah, we wouldn't even feed rotten rice
to a mutt like you, Sang-gil.
But you want us to make you chief?
We have had it with your crap!
How dare you. Really?
You don't even… you don't even know!
You don't have a clue
what really happened.
All she said was that
her feet were asleep, okay?
Yeah, right.
While your poor wife is aching all over.
Some role model.
Dragging Ae-sun's family into the race.
So her son is a bit of a troublemaker.
Does that make her one too?
My son is smart in his own way.
So what? What now, Ae-sun?
What'll you do? Are you gonna tell on me?
Naturally, naturally,
we will tell everyone and rat you out.
We'll tell everyone,
and Ae-sun will be chief.
That's right.
Is that a fact?
Is that the way you wanna win?
People have a right
to know who we are.
It's not talking trash.
It's just discussing morality.
Everyone has the right to know
their candidates, right?
That's what you said, isn't it?
- Oh, Ae-sun!
- Oh.
You little…
You shouldn't have.
THE 7TH DODONG-RI CHIEF, OH AE-SUN
Oh my!
Ae-sun! Oh Ae-sun!
Oh Ae-sun! Oh Ae-sun!
Ae-sun gave it
her best shot once again.
Oh, look!
Wow, the school lent this to us?
They only use it
for sports day once a year.
Wow.
She hit the bull's-eye
right in the middle.
- That day, Jeju Island…
- Chief!
- …got its first-ever female village chief.
- Hey, Chief.
Chief! Oh, hey!
Uh, yes?
- Look, the rice cake is here.
- Oh, bring it out.
- Chief Oh, we're out of makgeolli.
- Oh, really?
Chief Oh, any more blankets?
- Uh-huh!
- Chief!
It's the school asking if you can return
the banner by sports day, if that's okay?
It pulled
at her heartstrings.
Many years later, when
Mom joined Lim Young-woong's fan club,
her username was Chief Oh.
Hey, Chief Oh!
Come over here and have a taste of this!
You have first dibs!
Okay.
Okay!
- These are ready.
- Okay.
There she is!
THE 5TH AND 6TH FISHING CO-OP CHIEF
BU SANG-GIL
Here, eat, eat, eat, eat.
I made so much.
One more time!
You serving meat at this thing?
Or are you too goddamn cheap?
Goodness. What's the point
of sitting here all angry?
Why would I miss
my successor's inauguration ceremony?
She doesn't know anything
about being chief.
She needs all the advice she can get.
Well, if you weren't here,
you'd seem a small man indeed.
For your information, I have resigned.
I stepped down on my own accord.
You know the 80-year-old grandpa
who runs the convenience store?
He's never said more than
two words to me before,
but the other day, he asked if I knew
about Sang-gil and the foot massage.
Oh, come on. How many times
do I have to say her feet were asleep?
I would have done the same for anyone.
I'll be serving
my daughter-in-law the rest of my life.
Everyone in the family
is a bigwig politician now.
If Ae-sun is the chief,
her husband's the consort,
and I'm sort of like the queen mother.
Jeez. So, yet again,
she is completely lost in her delusions.
Isn't she something else?
Ever since she met Gwan-sik,
things turned around for her.
I can't tell if you're showing off or not.
Showing off?
How's your daughter-in-law?
Still a gambler, no?
Gambler?
Hurry! We're out of pajeon!
- Jeez.
- The First Gentleman is super busy.
Don't call him First Gentleman.
Good lord, son,
do you have to wear that apron?
- Hey, Ma?
- What?
Can you make them a little bigger? Please?
Why, that…
Now he's pissing me off.
I think I understand.
You're happy Ae-sun is the chief,
but you're also not.
What's so funny?
I've never seen you before. You know me?
Yes, Chief Oh is on it!
I'll be right there!
- Oh my goodness!
- Now what's wrong?
Like you never saw
your mother-in-law at work?
Is this revenge?
Your way of getting back at me?
Please, I'm not talking about that.
Sure.
Why are you making
my opponent's wife make our jeon?
It's unbelievable, but true!
Bu Sang-gil massaged her feet!
Don't listen to them.
You know how an election can get.
Everyone shares all the negative stories
they can think of,
even about your great-great-grandfather.
You should've told them
that I went dancing back then.
No one ever found that out.
I'm very sorry.
I feel like I insulted you
discussing your sensitive issues.
By the way, just between you and me,
we took care of
the real estate lady on our end.
I don't care about her.
Gyeong-suk from the salon.
Mi-suk from the real estate office.
Well, for such a tiny island,
there are so many women
with such a bad taste in men.
However,
it's true that I'm the worst of them all.
Listen, why don't you go home?
People want to gossip.
You know, that's all.
You think they're saying
I have no self-respect?
No, I only meant that I feel awful
seeing you make jeon for our party.
I want to, though,
because it's my prerogative.
I have every right to be here.
Besides, I voted for you.
So, at the very least,
I think I deserve a drink
that you pour me yourself.
Yeong-ran, listen.
When you go home,
no, until the day you die,
tell your husband you voted for him, hmm?
Hey, Yeong-ran,
who did you vote for?
Why can't you answer me?
You didn't vote for me.
Come on, now.
What are you picking on Mom for?
Hey, you little brat.
Don't you disrespect me. What do you know?
You don't know jack shit about anything.
Why? Why? Tell me why.
Why did the governor come today?
Why would the governor come
to a village chief's inauguration?
He didn't come to mine!
The governor?
Gwan-sik got a plaque of honor.
That's why the governor attended.
For jumping into the water?
If I saw someone drowning,
I would jump in a hundred times.
I'd get a hundred commendations!
Wow. I heard there was a reward,
that they're getting a trip and stuff.
That's right.
The governor likes Gwan-sik.
He really does.
Of course he does.
Why? Why?
Why does everyone here just love
that little stupid punk? Why?
GOVERNOR HWANG IN-SU
CONGRATULATIONS ON YOUR INAUGURATION
If your grandma were alive,
she would've drowned her in red beans.
Come on, let's dance the night away!
My God. What's going on over here?
Come on!
You ought to be ashamed of yourself!
We're going home!
Dad, you have to stop her. She's so drunk!
Goodness. She loves Busan, doesn't she?
She calls herself a bookworm.
You're no bookworm! Just a lousy dancer!
Do you see
what she's doing with that pole?
Go throw those red beans at her.
Dad!
Leave her alone.
Let her have her fun, kid.
I'm so glad I have a dog.
Oh, where is he?
Let's go, Duraengi.
Here, Duraengi. Here, boy.
Let's go, honey.
That's a good boy.
Hey, Dad.
I can take her.
You happy?
Yeah.
I am.
I'm so happy.
You're not a vice president,
a deputy director, or a deputy chief.
You're chief, period.
You know, it's strange.
Even though I've finally lost the "deputy"
from my title after 30 years,
the person I wanna tell the most
isn't here.
I wouldn't say I wanna go back
to my childhood, because it was horrible,
but if there were any way I could go back,
I think I would.
If only for the chance
to hold my mother's hand one more time.
Do you know the reason
why I became the vice president now?
It's so that I can be chief in the future.
It's like diving.
You start in the shallow water,
then go deeper.
Little by little, I'll build experience
and become chief one day.
There's no one on the island
more powerful than a chief.
Even Auntie Gyeong-ja never forgets
to pay her loans back.
Okay, one day, you'll be chief
so I can be the chief's mother.
Will you make rice cake when it happens?
I'm going to make so much rice cake,
it'll pile up as high as a mountain.
- You'd be happy?
- Uh-huh. I'd be happy.
Very much so.
Actually, I'm holding back.
I'm saving up all my happiness
for when that day comes.
Go on, take as much as you want.
I want everyone to know how happy I am.
I'm not holding back.
- Ooh!
- Go on.
- Double portions for everyone.
- Oh, goodness, look.
Oh my.
With these nets,
you supported me when my mom couldn't.
Now she needs you
to brag about me for her.
- Oh my.
- Oh, goodness.
You must've had a lot of rice.
Why did you make so much?
This is Gwang-rye's doing.
Thank you, Gwang-rye, for the rice!
Oh my.
Gwang-rye.
If you could only see your daughter now.
Grown-up and the village chief.
Remember when she was ten years old?
I can still see her wearing
her funeral dress.
Poor dear.
I wondered if she'd make it.
Who knew that not only
would she make it, but she would thrive?
If Gwang-rye were with us,
she'd drum and play
all around Mount Hallasan with us today.
You had to dig out the frozen ground
with your tiny, little hand
and bury your heart in it.
Your harvesting season has come at last.
Gwang-rye's persimmon tree
is growing well, isn't it?
Growing tall and strong.
It was now fall,
the season of harvest,
when all kinds of fruits
were ripening on the vine.
Their harvest was beginning
to overflow the basket.
But depending on where we were,
the sun bathed us in a different light.
Oh, look.
Why, uh…
- Huh?
- Why are you still in the front seat?
Oh.
You know,
it's fun sometimes.
Thanks again.
She can't stand seeing me in here.
Oh, that mean girl you told me about?
Yeah.
Yeong-beom!
Let me know
if you would like anything else, okay?
You also don't know whose car that is?
Something's up with Yang Geum-myeong.
Think about it.
Don't say stuff like that.
She may be poor, but she still has class.
And, Ye-rim,
stop taking her side.
Geum-myeong is never nice to you.
Why give her the benefit of the doubt?
It's how she shows displeasure.
In her own twisted way.
What do you mean?
My dad and I talked a bit about
Geum-myeong the other day.
He said it's a big fish
in a little pond situation.
She's used to being the best
at everything back at home.
However, up here in Seoul,
she's really not that special.
She must feel more inferior every day.
Dad says I should be
the bigger person and let her be.
That's what "class" is.
Okay.
But why would she act that way with you?
Her GPA is higher than yours.
By 0.2. Just by 0.2 points.
- She's taller.
- By two centimeters.
Also,
have you memorized everything about her?
- What do you mean?
- Doesn't matter.
No, tell me. "Doesn't matter" what?
I just meant
Geum-myeong was chosen
to study in Japan first.
If she hadn't passed it up, you wouldn't
have gotten the opportunity. Because of--
If it were up to me,
I'd have chosen her as well.
My family can afford to send me abroad.
It's only natural they would choose
someone from a less fortunate background.
Ye-rim.
Geum-myeong's family is just fine.
- Her father is a captain.
- Of a fishing boat!
Why are you defending her?
That's what class is about.
I'm not hungry.
She dumped you, didn't she?
What is that foreign car?
What is it? Tell me!
You are just dying to know, aren't you?
PRIVATE TUTORING BAN SPARKS ODDITIES
TUTORING EVEN TAKING PLACE IN MOVING CARS!
23RD TYPHOON "PHYLLIS"
CAUTIONS IN FISHING TOWNS
How are the waters today?
No matter how bad
the water might be,
my dad sails to sea.
And it makes me nervous.
- Bye.
- See you later.
Be safe.
- Let's roll.
- No.
- What?
- What did I say about being polite?
Shut the fuck up.
Whoa! Don't say "shut the fuck."
It's "Jesus Christ."
Ugh!
You can't even spell "Wednesday."
Where did you learn to swear?
Jesus!
Jenny, do you know
how to spell "Wednesday"? Write it out.
Write it out.
Oh, goodness gracious.
Why were you named "Jenny" anyway?
Is it to make people think
you're American or something?
If you were anyone else,
I'd have you fired.
I'd have you worse than fired.
Fire me, go ahead.
Why haven't you fired me already?
I heard none of your tutors
last more than a month.
Yeah, I can't wait.
Feet down!
Hey, Jenny.
You didn't memorize the vocab, did you?
You just come to my house to eat,
don't you?
Your housekeeper is good.
She can make food from anywhere.
This is from Busan. Glass noodles.
She just used our money
to impress people.
You're such a brat.
That lady will quit, too, because of you.
That lady has been here the longest.
Mom likes her, I guess.
You know, it seems like people don't stay
at your house for a very long time.
Why?
Also,
I still don't understand
why I've never met your mother or father.
So what? It's better that way.
I'd like to see their faces at least once.
Well, my mom's seen you.
That should be enough.
What? She saw me? Where?
Where was this?
You stapled a picture to your résumé.
Just hang around until your time's up.
I know you don't wanna be here anyway.
You're here for the money.
Well, aren't you a genius, Jenny.
And, yes, I want to be paid.
Ms. Yang, can't you fix your bangs
or change where
you part your hair at least?
You don't look like you're from Seoul.
Fix them?
Why are you so worried about my hairstyle?
I mean, it's not like
you and I look that much alike.
What?
But… I am the sexier one.
Sexy? Sexy?
Here.
That's a new vocab word. Spell it.
Come on, that's easy. S-E--
Enough.
- S-E…
- I said, enough!
That's all you're interested in, huh?
Little brat, you.
Just take what you're owed.
Don't take more than that.
Your mother is getting to me.
I'm tempted more
every single time, you know.
Hello?
Yeah, what?
Just grab a handful.
Take double for teaching that brat.
What?
Mom's coming. She wants to see you.
- What? Right now?
- Just go.
Go now, girl.
Yes, Ms. Yang,
that's real white porcelain.
I see.
I have everything now.
I have blue porcelain,
and I have white as well.
Everything.
Everything except a good education.
W… wow.
I have such deep regret
for my lack of education.
I was hoping to be able
to live through my daughter,
but she has my intellect, unfortunately.
We'll raise her grades little by little.
Don't worry.
Sadly, there's no time for that now.
Life doesn't wait for anyone.
We all know that.
Ah…
Uh, then does that mean I'm fired?
Jenny is very wealthy,
but she isn't that clever,
while you are very smart
and not much else.
So let's try work this out together.
I'll set things up
and take care of everything.
You just follow my lead and directions.
It took us two years to find a tutor
that looked like our daughter.
Her college exams are very soon.
You should take the exams for her.
That's what I'm demanding of you,
Ms. Yang.
Uh…
STUDENT ID
OH JENNY
TEST IDENTIFICATION SLIP
If she gets into a top-three university,
I'll buy you a 1,300-square-foot apartment
and a 1,000-square-foot one
for other colleges.
NOTICE
LIST OF APPROVED APPLICANTS FOR DORMS
If her name
isn't here, she can't live in the dorms?
No.
Then a boarding house.
How much is the rent there?
A lot.
It'll be expensive.
What?
Is he trying to fight?
The eyes of the world
are upon us
as a historical presidential election
unfolds today, on December 16th.
It has been 16 years since our citizens
have been able
to directly vote for the president.
The atmosphere is solemn.
They say the dorm selection is by lottery,
but I think there are backdoor deals.
We all know supposedly
"clean" organizations can be shady.
Right?
…president of their choice.
So… who are you voting for?
…government has declared today
a temporary…
I think we need to call
the military police.
Excuse me?
Why is there
a soldier outside the girls' dorm?
The guys' dorms are nearby.
Usually, when there's a break,
they come in and out.
So who'd you vote for?
…had given their all
to ask for each of their votes.
You think they will be able
to arrest that guy?
One.
One, two, three.
Oh!
Sir, good to meet you again.
Remember me, sir?
We met at the admission ceremony.
I'm Park Yeong-beom,
and your daughter and I,
we are friends.
I recall on that day, I actually took
a few pictures of you guys.
You were saying how
you took a plane to see Geum-myeong,
then you took a bus.
Yeah.
What kind of friend?
- Sir?
- I asked you a question.
- Yeah?
- You're a friend of my daughter.
Well, so tell me,
what kind of friend are you, boy?
TEST IDENTIFICATION SLIP
OH JENNY
Oh my God.
Oh.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
This seems kind of risky.
Tutoring is already illegal.
In fact, every time I come here,
I get nervous.
Takes nerve to earn
any money in this world, dear.
You can't win if you risk nothing at all.
If I get caught, I'd be expelled.
That's why you're getting an apartment,
to compensate you
for the risk of expulsion.
Hold on, this exam is serious.
You really think I can be Jenny?
Whoever the proctor is,
I'll have greased their palm.
I will arrange everything for you nicely
so you won't have a reason
to be worried at all.
Doesn't everyone make their money
by doing what they're good at?
I will assist you
by doing what I'm good at.
Isn't it right and honorable
to make a living using your talents?
Just turn a blind eye this once
and take the apartment.
There's just one thing--
No, dear.
I don't wanna hear it.
Before you speak, think carefully about
what you stand to lose.
You're running out of scholarship money,
and you have to leave the dorms.
Forget about studying abroad.
How… do you know all that?
As I said, think carefully.
Think of your parents who worked so hard
to get you to where you are, Ms. Yang.
You're a fish
trying to get out of her pond,
but that pond is getting dry. Hmm?
Follow me.
Hey. Go to your room.
Young lady!
Hey, young lady!
Oh my.
Did you just leave unit 908?
Yes? What's this about?
You ran so fast,
I wasn't able to catch up.
What? Why would I run?
You stole something from that family?
Huh?
Come. Just give it here.
Don't make any more trouble.
Um, is that what she said?
I don't need
an answer from you right now.
Just take these with you.
Look at it as many times as you need,
then tell me your decision, okay?
Nobody wants to be stuck
in a small pond, do they?
It's just too sad to contemplate.
Imagine, instead,
how you'd be able to give
your mother and father the whole world.
That poor father of yours.
Always riding his boat.
He'll have to ride in that boat
for the rest of his life.
I remember my father.
He trusted his eldest son to pass the bar,
and he was stuck tending his cows
until the day he died.
When I think of my parents
and how they're struggling,
there's nothing to think about here.
What's better than earning an apartment
doing what I'm good at?
Yes, that's what I wanna hear.
I remember what my mom and dad taught me.
What?
I was taught it was better to fail a class
than cheat my way in.
I was taught not to take money I found
but to report it instead.
I know my parents wouldn't want me to live
as a fraud or a scammer.
Huh? What exactly
are you trying to say to me?
Just
that if I take the test
and Jenny gets accepted somehow,
then a girl like me won't, and
I can't stand the idea
of taking it from her.
If she found out about it,
she would die of heartbreak.
Yang Geum-myeong, listen to me.
It's one thing
to stand for your principles
when you have the proper means,
but to do it when you have nothing
is simply recklessness.
I'd say sending a girl
who can't even spell
to an elite school would be reckless.
Would you?
I think you
should let Jenny find out
what she's really good at.
Isn't that the right and honorable thing
to do for Jenny?
Yeah, I'd rather be a singer.
I am leaving now.
All you little fish
are exactly the same.
You have nothing to your name,
so all you have to live for is preserving
your pathetic sense of pride!
Jenny was always a pain in the ass.
I think I deserve a raise after all this.
You know I'm not a thief.
Oh yes, I know.
I'm just keeping out of that bully's way.
All the cash in the world
can't buy my integrity.
The ring?
What?
You know, the diamond ring.
My parents always hoped…
…that away from their arms,
my life would be rosy, easy, and carefree.
Open up!
Ma'am, open up!
Hey, Jenny! Open the door, come on!
I didn't steal anything!
Hey! You know I'm not a thief! Open up!
But the truth is,
the world away from their arms
was a jungle.
"IN THE HOPE THAT OUR ECHOES
WILL FLOW AND FLOW, UNTIL THEY REACH YOU."